Guide to the George A. Lindbeck Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Writings, 1941-2006, n.d.; Series II
  - Articles: Ecumenism
    - General
      - "Two Types of Ecumenism", nd (Box 9, Folder 160)
      - "Pluralism", nd (Box 56, Folder 1301)
      - "Die Erklarung Uber Die Religionsfreiheit", nd (Box 56, Folder 1301)
    - Lutheran
      - "II: Christian Witness and Lutheran Presence" in Worldview, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 161)
      - "Ecumenism and the Lutheran Church in Malaysia and Singapore" (unpublished) (Box 9, Folder 162)
      - "Impressions of the Lutheran Presence in the Holy Land" (draft), 1979 (Box 9, Folder 163)
      - "Lutheranism as Church and Movement: Trends in America since 1980" in Lutheran Theological Seminary Bulletin, v.71 n.1, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 164)
      - "Facing Unity: A Conversation with George A. Lindbeck" in Lutheran Partners, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 165)
      - "The Confessions as Ideology and Witness in the History of Lutheranism" in Lutheran World (Box 9, Folder 166)
      - "Open Letter" in Forum Letter, v. 11 n.7, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 167)
      - "Book of Concord: Interpreting the Book of Concord on its 400th Anniversary"; "Lutheran Identity: A Comparative Study of the Confessional Positions of the Book of Concord on its 450th Anniversary", 1978; 1978 (Box 9, Folder 168)
      - "Reception and Method: Reflections on the Ecumenical Role of the LWF" (drafts) (Box 9, Folder 169)
      - "Reception and Method: Reflections on the Ecumenical Role of the LWF" in Ecumenical Methodology (Box 9, Folder 170)
      - "Readiness for Ministry and Confessional Standards: An Analysis of Lutheran Responses" (Box 9, Folder 171)
    - Lutheran-Catholic Dialogue
      - "Impressions from Helsinki, Rome and Montreal" in Catholic World, v.198 n.1, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 172)
      - Comments on 'Why Christian Unity?' in New Haven Register, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 173)
      - "Answer to the Second of the Roman Catholic Questions to Lutherans from the San Francisco Meeting" (draft), 1969 (Box 9, Folder 174)
      - "The Reformation and the Infallibility Debate" (unpublished), 1974 (Box 9, Folder 175)
      - "Justification in the Catholic-Lutheran Dialogues and in the Discussions of the Recognition of the Augsburg Confession" Minneapolis Meeting of Lutheran-Roman Catholic Dialogue, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 176)
      - "Some Patristic Views on the Relationship of Faith and Works in Justification", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 177)
      - "What is New in Our Statement? The Essence of the Argument", 1982 (Box 9, Folder 178)
      - "Memorandum on the Future Dialogue of the Lutheran World Federation and the Roman Catholic Secretariat for Christian Unity" (unpublished), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 179)
      - "Open Letter" in Forum Letter, v.24 n.4, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 180)
      - "A Protestant View of the Ecclesiological Status of the Roman Catholic Church" in Journal of Ecumenical Studies, v.1 n.2, nd (Box 10, Folder 181)
      - "Article IV and Lutheran-Roman Catholic Dialogue: The Limits of Diversity in Understanding of Justification" (Box 10, Folder 182)
      - "The Augsburg Confession in the Light of Contemporary Catholic-Lutheran Dialogue" in The Role of the Augsburg Confession: Catholic and Lutheran Views, Fortress Press (Box 10, Folder 183)
      - "The Future of the Interconfessional Discussion on Ministry", nd (Box 10, Folder 184)
      - "The Future of Roman Catholic-Lutheran Dialogue" (Box 10, Folder 185)
      - "Justification by Faith" (drafts), nd (Box 10, Folder 186)
      - "Justification by Faith: an analysis of the 1983 report of the U.S. Lutheran-Roman Catholic Dialogue" in LCA Partners December 1984/January 1985 (Box 92, Folder 1)
      - "Justification II: The Sixteenth Century Conflict" (draft), nd (Box 10, Folder 187)
      - "A Lutheran View of Intercommunion with Roman Catholics; Intercommunion Between Lutherans and Roman Catholics?"; A Response (Box 10, Folder 188)
      - "A Lutheran Reaction to the Statement on Justification", nd (Box 10, Folder 189)
      - Lindbeck Interview (Box 10, Folder 190)
      - "The Recovery of Catholicity: Can the Augsburg Confession Become What it was Originally Intended to Be?" (Box 10, Folder 191)
      - "Reform and the Council" in Lutheran World, v.9 n.4; "Liturgical Reform in the Second Vatican Council" in Lutheran World, v. 10 n.2; "On Councils: Impressions from Helsinki, Rome and Montreal" in Lutheran World, v.11 n.1 (2 copies of each volume) (Box 10, Folder 192)
      - "Liturgische Reform auf dem Zweiten Vatikanischen Konzil" in Lutherische Rundschau, 13. Jahrgang Heft 2, 1963 April (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Catholic
      - General
        - Contribution to the Symposium "On a Roman Catholic President" in The American Lutheran, v. XLIII n.7, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 193)
        - re: Presidency in American Lutheran, v. XLIII, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 194)
        - "Ecclesiology and Roman Catholic Renewal" in Religion and Life, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 195)
        - "Ecclesiology and Roman Catholic Renewal" in Religion and Life, v. XXXIII, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 196)
        - "A New Vision of the World and the Ecumenical Revolution", 1966 (Box 10, Folder 197)
        - "The Roman Catholic View of Non-Christian Religions " in Methodist Message, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 198)
        - "John Courtney Murray, S.J.: An Evaluation" in Christianity and Crises, v. XXI, 1961; 1975 (Box 10, Folder 199)
        - "The Crisis in American Catholicism" in Our Common Heritage as Christians: Essays in Honor of Albert C. Outler ed. by John Deschner et al, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 1299)
        - "American Roman Catholicism", nd (Box 10, Folder 200)
        - "Catholicisme Americain" in Le Semeur, nd (Box 10, Folder 201)
        - "Ecumenical Aspects of Catholic Theology in the Last 20 Years", nd (Box 10, Folder 202)
        - "Roman Catholicism on the Eve of the Council" in The Papal Council and the Gospel (Box 10, Folder 203)
        - "Some Lutheran Reflections on Trent", nd (Box 10, Folder 204)
      - Mariology
        - "Mariology", nd (Box 10, Folder 205)
      - Papacy
        - "Session II: Problems on the Road to Unity, Infallibility", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 206)
        - "Lutherans and the Papacy", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 207)
        - "The Present Ecumenical Consideration of Priesthood, Episcopacy, and Papacy (Box 56, Folder 1302)
      - Vatican II
        - "Should U.S. Send Ambassador to Vatican?" in Foreign Policy Bulletin, v. XXXI n.7; other related materials and drafts, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 208)
        - "The Future of Roman Catholic Theology in the Light of the First Session of the Second Vatican Council" in Dialog, v. II, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 209)
        - "So Far, Surprisingly Good" in The National Lutheran, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 210)
        - "The Second Vatican Council" in Concordia Theological Monthly, v. XXXIV n. 1, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 211)
        - "Vatican Council II and the Future of the Dialogue with Rome" in Helsinki, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 212)
        - "The Declaration of Religious Liberty", 1964 (Box 11, Folder 213)
        - "The Vatican Council and Latin American Lutherans" in World Encounter, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 214)
        - "A Definitive Look at Vatican II" in Christianity and Crisis, v. XXV n.23, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 215)
        - "A Loyola Symposium: The Church Since Vatican II" in Loyola Magazine, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 216)
        - "Critique of De Ecclesia: A Protestant Point of View", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 217)
        - "World, Church, and Mission: A Protestant Evaluation of the Theology of the Second Vatican Council," a draft of a portion of the book Future of Roman Catholic Theology (Box 11, Folder 218)
        - "The Vatican Council," a Proposed Book on the Vatican II, nd (Box 11, Folder 219)
    - Evangelism
      - "The Evangelical Possibilities of Roman Catholic Theology" in Lutheran World, nd (Box 11, Folder 220)
      - "Theology of Evangelism", nd (Box 11, Folder 221)
    - Ministry
      - "The Sacramentality of the Ministry: Karl Rahner and a Protestant View" in Oecumenica: Jahrbuch fur okumenische Forschung, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 222)
      - "Karl Rahner and a Protestant View of the Sacramentality of the Ministry" in T he Catholic Theological Society of America, 1966 (Box 56, Folder 1302)
      - "A Critique of Philip J. Hefner's Paper on Episcopacy" for Commission on the Comprehensive Study of the Doctrine of the Ministry, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1302)
      - "The Lutheran Doctrine of the Ministry: Catholic and Reformed" in Theological Studies, v.20 n.4, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 223)
    - Infallibility
      - "Reform and Infallibility" in Cross Currents, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 224)
      - "Reform and Infallibility" in Cross Currents, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 225)
      - "Reform and Infallibility" in Cross Currents, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 226)
      - "A Protestant Perspective" in America, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 227)
      - "Problems on the Road to Unity: Infallibility", 1973 (Box 11, Folder 228)
      - "Roman Catholic and Lutherans on Teaching Authority and Infallibility" in Ecumenical Trends, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 229)
      - "The Meaning of Infallibility: A Study of Theological Language", nd (Box 11, Folder 230)
      - "Theories of Doctrine: Infallibility", nd (Box 11, Folder 231)
  - Articles: Theology
    - General
      - "A Note on Aristotle's Discussion of God and the World" in The Review of Metaphysics, v.II n.5, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 232)
      - "Cosmological Arguments: A Description, Classification, and Evaluation", 1948 (Box 11, Folder 233)
      - "A Great Scotist Study" in The Review of Metaphysics, v. VII n.3, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 234)
      - Wesleyan Public Affairs Center discussions of Body-Soul Relationships, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 235)
      - "Nominalism and the Problem of Meaning as Illustrated by Pierre D'Ailly on Predestination and Justification" (draft), 1959 (Box 11, Folder 236)
      - "Nominalism and the Problem of Meaning as Illustrated by Pierre D'Ailly on Predestination and Justification" in The Harvard Theological Review, v. LII n.1, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 237)
      - "Natural Law in the Thought of Paul Tillich" in Natural Law Forum, v.7, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 238)
      - "Sociological Studies and Ecclesiology in America" (unpublished), 1963 (Box 12, Folder 239)
      - "The Thought of Karl Rahner, S.J." in Christianity and Crisis, v. XXV n.17, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 240)
      - "The Problem of Doctrinal Development and Contemporary Protestant Theology" in Concilium: An International Review of Theology, v.1 n.3, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 241)
      - "Theology of Hope", 1970 (Box 12, Folder 242)
      - " Fides ex auditu and the Salvation of Non-Christians" in The Mission of the Church, 1973 (Box 56, Folder 1300)
      - "Theologische Methode and Wissenschaftstheorie" in Theologische Revue, 1978 (Box 56, Folder 1300)
      - "The Bible as Realistic Narrative" in Consensus in Theology ed. by Leonared Swidler, 1980 (Box 56, Folder 1299)
      - "The American Crisis of Religion in a Postliberal Age", 1985 (Box 12, Folder 243)
      - "An Appreciation or Against the Stream", 1987 (Box 12, Folder 244)
      - "Chapter Three: Liturgy and the Message of Salvation" (Box 12, Folder 245)
      - "The Limits of the Development and Reformation of Doctrine" (Box 12, Folder 246)
      - "Politics and Original Sin: The Uses and Abuses of a Doctrine" (Box 12, Folder 247)
      - "Protestant Problems with Lonergan on Development of Dogma" (Box 12, Folder 248)
      - "There is No Protestant Church" in Una Sancta, v.23 n.1, nd (Box 12, Folder 249)
    - Aquinas
      - "Participation and Existence in the Interpretation of St. Thomas Aquinas" in Franciscan Studies, v.17 n.1, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 250)
      - "Thomism: Barrier or Bridge" in Operation Understanding, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 251)
      - "The A Priori in St. Thomas' Theory of Knowledge", nd (Box 12, Folder 252)
      - "The Ecumenical Aquinas: An Evaluation of Efforts to Reconcile St. Thomas and Luther" (Box 12, Folder 253)
      - Introduction to "The Nature and Validity of Thomistic Analogy" (unpublished) (Box 12, Folder 254)
      - "Doctrine in Christianity: A Comparison with Judaism" in meeting of American Theological Society, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 255)
    - Early Christianity
      - "Philosophy and 'Existenz' in Early Christianity" in The Review of Metaphysics, v.X n.3, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 256)
      - "The Soteriological Motivations of the Ancient Creeds" (unpublished), 1960 (Box 12, Folder 257)
    - Education
      - "Theological Studies in a University Seminary", 1972 (Box 12, Folder 258)
      - "The Place of Scholarship in a University Seminary" in Reflection, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 259)
      - "University Divinity Schools: A Report Ecclesiastically Independent Theological Education; Memorandum on Theological Education" in Working Papers: The Rockefeller Foundation, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 260)
      - "Theological Education in North America Today" in The Council on the Study of Religion Bulletin, 1977 (Box 56, Folder 1302)
      - "The Future of Lutheran Theological Education", 1986 (Box 12, Folder 261)
      - "Election, Christian Apostasy, and the Holocaust" (unpublished), 1971 (Box 12, Folder 262)
    - Medieval
      - "Abelard, Peter", nd (Box 12, Folder 263)
      - "The Contrast Between Reformation and Medieval Roman Catholic Views of the Ministry, especially of its Sacramentality" (Box 12, Folder 264)
      - "The Word of God in the Middle Ages" in Una Sancta, nd (Box 12, Folder 265)
    - Local
      - "Hartford and History" (Box 12, Folder 266)
  - Worship
    - "Easter Meditations", nd (Box 12, Folder 267)
    - Yale Divinity School Chapel Talks, nd (Box 12, Folder 268)
    - Non-Yale Sermons and Talks (Box 12, Folder 269)
  - Labor and Religion
    - "The N.A.M. Organizes Church and Industry Conferences", 1945 (Box 13, Folder 270)
  - Book Reviews
    - "Hans Kung, Rechtfertigung " in Ecumenical Review, v. XI, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 271)
    - " Revelation, Natural Law and the Thought of Reinhold Niebuhr" in Natural Law Forum, v.4 n.1, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 272)
    - "J. Pelikan, The Riddle of Roman Catholicism " in Lutheran World, v. VII, 1960-61 (Box 13, Folder 273)
    - "Scharlemann's MS", 1961 (Box 13, Folder 274)
    - "R. McAfee Brown and G. Weigel, An American Dialogue; W. Cowan, Facing Protestant-Roman Catholic Tension; J. Kerwin, Catholic Viewpoint on Church and State " in Saturday Review, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 275)
    - "H. Daniel-Rops, The Second Vatican Council; H. Kung, The Council, Reform and Reunion/Cross Currents; E. Fairweather and E. Hardy, The Voice of the Church: The Ecumenical Council " in Dialog, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 276)
    - "St. Thomas Aquinas" in Summa Theologiae, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 277)
    - Reviews of Dialogue on the way; Protestants report from Rome on the Vatican Council, edited by George A. Lindbeck, 1965-1966 (Box 56, Folder 1308)
    - "Edward Schillebeeckx, Revelation and Theology " in Christian Century, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 278)
    - "Karl Rahner, Obedience and the Church " in Christian Century, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 279)
    - "Rosemary Ruether, The Reformer and the Radical " in Journal of Ecumenical Studies, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 280)
    - "David Tracy, The Achievement of Bernard Lonergan " in Christian Century, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 281)
    - "J.M. Domenach and R. de Montvalon, The Catholic Avant-Garde: French Catholicism Since WWII " (Box 13, Folder 282)
    - "Rudolph J. Ehrlich, Rome-Opponent or Partner? ", nd (Box 13, Folder 283)
    - "Donald L. Gelpi, S.J. Life and Light " (Box 13, Folder 284)
    - "Paul Hinnebusch, Dynamic Contemplation: Inner LIfe for Modern Man ", nd (Box 13, Folder 285)
    - "Hans Kung, Infallible? An Inquiry ", nd (Box 13, Folder 286)
    - "M. Murray, The Thought of Teilhard de Chardin; C. Mooney, Teilhard de Chardin and the Mysteryof Christ; J. Kopp, Teilhard de Chardin " (Box 13, Folder 287)
    - "R. Norris, God and World in Early Christian Theology; H. von Campenhausen, Men Who Shaped the Western Church " (Box 13, Folder 288)
    - "Otto Piper, Protestantism in an Ecumenical Age " in Denominationalism and Ecumenism (Box 13, Folder 289)
    - "Karl Rahner, Theological Investigations, v. VI ", nd (Box 13, Folder 290)
    - "A Radical Book: Brothers in Hope ", nd (Box 13, Folder 291)
    - " Concilium v.1, 2, 4, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25 ", nd (Box 13, Folder 292)
    - " Dennoch Bruder, Die Steine des Anstosses, Christen Suchen Eine Kirche, On in Christ, Die Katholizitat der Kirche, Skandalon " (Box 13, Folder 293)
    - " Zur Kontraversthaloge " in Lutheran World, nd (Box 13, Folder 294)
    - Miscellaneous (English), nd (Box 13, Folder 295)
    - Miscellaneous (English), nd (Box 13, Folder 296)
    - Miscellaneous (German), nd (Box 13, Folder 297)
    - "Christians Between Arabs and Jews" in Christian Jewish Relations, 1980 (Box 56, Folder 1302)
  - Articles: Miscellaneous
    - "In Memory of Sydney Ahlstrom 1919-1984" in Reflection (Box 56, Folder 1301)
    - "Two Readings in Memory of Roberty Lowry Calhoun", 1984 (Box 56, Folder 1301)
    - Miscellaneous (German), nd (Box 13, Folder 298)
    - Miscellaneous (French, Spanish and Italian) (Box 14, Folder 299)
    - Miscellaneous, nd (Box 14, Folder 300)
  - Addendum
    - Articles and essays: Ecumenism
      - General
        - "The Reformation in an Ecumenical Age" in The Princeton Seminary Bulletin v. LXI no. 1, 1967 (Box 88, Folder 8)
        - "The Church" in Keeping the Faith (George Wainwright, ed.), 1988 (Box 71, Folder 126)
        - "Two Kinds of Ecumenism: Unitive and Interdenominational" in Gregorianum, v. 70, n. 4, 1989 (Box 71, Folder 127)
        - "Confession and Community: An Israel-like View of the Church" in The Christian Century, v. 107, n. 16, 1990 (Box 71, Folder 128)
        - "An Israel-like Church: Scripture, Ecclesiology and Ecumenism in a Postmodern Age", 1990 (Box 71, Folder 129)
        - "The Structure of the Communio", 1991 (Box 71, Folder 130)
        - "Ecumenical Imperatives for the Twenty-first Century" in Currents in Theology and Mission, 1993 (Box 89, Folder 13)
        - "The Gospel's Uniqueness: Election and Untranslatability" in Modern Theology, v. 13, n. 4, 1997 (Box 71, Folder 131)
        - "The Church as Israel: An Ecumenical Ecclesiology", 1998 (Box 71, Folder 132)
        - "The Eucharist Tastes Bitter in the Divided Church" in Spectrum, v. 19, n. 1, 1999 (Box 71, Folder 133)
        - In One Body Through the Cross: The Princeton Proposal for Christian Unity: A Call to the Churches from an Ecumenical Study Group (Carl E. Braaten and Robert W. Jenson, eds.), 2003 (Box 71, Folder 134)
        - "Non-Theological Factors and Structures of Unity"; "Faith and Religious Liberty" (draft); "Ecumenical Theology"; "Issue: The Divided Church" (unpublished) (Box 71, Folder 135)
        - "Theology and Ecumenism Since Vatican II" (Box 90, Folder 1)
        - "Bishops and the Ministry of the Gospel: A Commentary on CA 5, 14 and 28" - Avery Dulles, co-author (Box 90, Folder 2)
        - "What I Think of the Catholic Church", n.d. (Box 90, Folder 6)
        - "Theologische Begrundung der Stiftung fur okumenische Forschung" (Box 90, Folder 7)
        - "Roman Catholic Ecumenicism and the Protestant Churches" (Box 90, Folder 7)
        - "Vatican II and Protestant Self-Understanding" (Box 90, Folder 8)
        - "The Catholic Challenge to Protestant Thought", no date (Box 92, Folder 9)
        - "Confessional Subscription in an Ecumenical Age" (for Word & World), 1991 (Box 92, Folder 10)
      - Lutherans
        - 1961 (Box 88, Folder 1)
        - "Impressions of the Lutheran Presence in the Holy Land" (unpublished report); "Christian Witness and Lutheran Presence", 1979 (Box 71, Folder 136)
        - "Luther on Law in Ecumenical Context" in Dialog, v. 22, n. 4, 1983 (Box 71, Folder 137)
        - Letter to Forum readers re. Seventh Assembly of Lutheran World Federation, 1984 (Box 88, Folder 30)
      - Lutheran-Catholic Dialogue
        - "The Lutheran Doctrine of the Ministry: Catholic and Reformed" in Theological Studies, v. 30, n. 4, 1969 (Box 72, Folder 138)
        - "Steps to Advance Lutheran/Roman Catholic Relations", 1993 (Box 89, Folder 14)
        - "Catholics and Lutherans on Teaching Authority and Infallibility" (draft) (Box 72, Folder 139)
        - "Augsburg and Ecclesia de Eucharistia" (Box 90, Folder 3)
        - "Episcopacy and the Unification of the Churches: Two Approaches" (Box 90, Folder 5)
      - Papacy
        - "Lutherans and the Papacy" (Box 72, Folder 140)
      - Vatican II
        - Summary Report of the Lutheran Observers on the First Session of Vatican Council II, 1962 (Box 88, Folder 2)
        - "Reminiscences of Vatican II", 1993 (Box 72, Folder 141)
        - "Progress in Textual Reasoning: From Vatican II to the Conference at Drew" (draft), 1996 (Box 72, Folder 142)
      - Infallibility
        - "The Reformation and the Infallibility Debate", 1974 (Box 72, Folder 143)
        - Untitled paper re. papal infallibility, 1975 (Box 88, Folder 17)
    - Articles and essays: Theology
      - "Theology of Hope" (draft), 1970 (Box 72, Folder 144)
      - "Creed and Confession" in Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1974 (Box 72, Folder 145)
      - Critique de L'Eglise et Doctrine de la Justification in Concilium 118, with handwritten essay, 1976 (Box 88, Folder 24)
      - "An Assessment Reassessed: Paul Tillich on the Reformation" in The Journal of Religion, v. 63, n. 4, 1983 (Box 72, Folder 146)
      - "The Story-Shaped Church: Critical Exegesis and Theological Interpretation" in Scriptural Authority and Narrative Interpretation (Garrett Green, ed.), 1987 (Box 72, Folder 147)
      - "Doctrine in Christianity: A Comparison with Judaism" (draft), 1987 (Box 72, Folder 148)
      - "Hans Frei and Biblical Narrative: The Prospects for a Postmodern Anselmianism" (draft), 1989 (Box 72, Folder 149)
      - Responses to "Hans Frei and Biblical Narrative: The Prospects for a Postmodern Anselmianism", 1989 (Box 89, Folder 7)
      - "The Gospel's Uniqueness: Election and Untranslatability", ca. 1996 (Box 90, Folder 4)
      - "Justification and Atonement: An Ecumenical Trajectory", late 1990s (Box 72, Folder 150)
      - No title, n. d. (Box 72, Folder 151)
      - "Postcritical Canonical Interpretation: Three Modes of Retrieval", n. d. (Box 72, Folder 152)
      - "Politics and Original Sin: The Uses and Abuses of Doctrine" (Box 72, Folder 153)
      - "Unbelievers and the "Sola Christi" (Box 90, Folder 19)
    - Articles and essays: Miscellaneous
      - No title - re. "organized Christianity", 1965 (Box 92, Folder 13)
      - "Possibilities of a Reluctant Socialism": Letter to editor of Worldview, 1977 (Box 92, Folder 8)
      - Preface for Ellen T. Charry's By the Renewing of Your Minds, 1999 (Box 72, Folder 154)
      - Foreword to German translation of The Nature of Doctrine, 1994 (Box 89, Folder 16)
      - "Erikson's Young Man Luther: A Historical and Theological Reappraisal (Box 90, Folder 18)
      - "Theologians, Theological Faculties and the ELCA Study of Ministry" (Box 90, Folder 20)
      - No title, n. d. (Box 72, Folder 156)
    - Edited works
      - Introduction to Lectures on the History of Christian Doctrine by Robert Lowry Calhoun, 2006 (Box 89, Folder 28)
      - Typescript ms. of "Lectures on the History of Christian Doctrine" by Robert Lowry Calhoun - Volume I - edited by George Lindbeck - for project resulting in Scripture, creed, theology: lectures on the history of Christian doctrine in the first centuries / Robert L. Calhoun; edited and with an introduction by George A. Lindbeck (Eugene: Cascade Books, 2011) (Box 89, Folder 29)